got nous
man Cal
down I applied for a pardon with Barack
Obama I was ignored he gave Manning a
commutation yeah Manning's still a
convicted felon you know and I'll tell
you another story that that answers that
question I have very very strong support
in the Greek American Community for a
for a pardon and I mean like the
Archbishop the the bishop of Pittsburgh
these two Greek American billionaires
the former lieutenant governor of New
York Alexi janulus the the Secretary of
State of of um Illinois great great
support two these two billionaires one
of them called me and I went up to New
York to meet with the two of them and
they said look we know Joe Biden very
well and we can get to him directly do
you want to meet with him and I said yes
so I said listen I have a letter signed
by 70 former CIA officers asking that I
be pardoned I have a letter written by
the man who wrote the law that I was
convicted of violating said saying I
should never have been charged in the
first place I have a floor statement
from John McCain saying I should be
pardoned from my liberal Democratic
Congressman saying I should be pardoned
but maybe most importantly right M I
have an oped from the Christian Science
monitor from Senator Joe Biden saying
that the law that I was convicted of
violating was unconstitutional and
should never have been
passed so we go to uh Wilmington to meet
with Biden this is like four or five
days before Trump became president so we
go to Biden I make my pitch and the two
Greeks and I got on the train we came to
um uh Washington I went home they went
to the White House for a dinner that
they were invited to I waited up late
into the night finally at at midnight
they called me and they said you would
have been so proud of Joe Biden tonight
he went to the mat for you but halfway
through his pitch
Obama put up his hands and said guys I'm
just not going to do this it's either
him or it's Manning and Manning got 30
years and I said why are we mutually
exclusive right what does it cost Barack
Obama to do the right
thing but he didn't do it and then
Honestly by the time Biden was able to
do it he was so demented that I mean I
don't I don't have any idea who made
that decision I don't think it was Biden
wow I don't know
wow yeah it sucks well at least you know
that a lot of people support you and you
know believe in you and and support your
work and tune yeah great pride in that
thank you and and you know what if I
could interrupt you for one second I
would do the whole dog on thing over
again really I would I mean my wife and
I split up um I lost my my pension I
lost my security clearance I lost my job
and I don't care because it was the
right thing to to do and torture is
outlawed in this country now and I'm
proud to have played a role in that you
know you you you come to some
issues
where you know that you're right and
they're wrong and eventually everybody
else is going to see that so I don't
care you know and this is one of the
things when you apply for a pardon when
you make a formal application we could
talk about the process whenever you want
um you have to show proof that you
showed contrition and I'm not contrite
oh yeah they're like are you sorry for
the crime you committed and I said no
I'm not no I would do it again did you
ever have regrets were you ever like God
why did I do the principal thing would
have been so much easier not to oh yeah
what moments of it yeah yeah when the
justice department offered me 45 years
in prison and told me that was the best
deal I was going to get I I intended to
commit suicide that night and my wife
and I were up watching TV and she said
let's go to bed and I said no I'm going
to stay up late I'm going to I'm going
to just watch TV I wasn't going to watch
TV I was going to go down to the garage
and just you know put a pipe in my mouth
and I think she sensed it and she said
no we should go to bed and she kind of
talked me out of it wow yeah so yeah
there were times when I I thought oh my
god what have I done what have I done
and then yeah the more I thought about
it the more I thought no somebody had to
do it we're led by a cabal of
criminals and somebody had to say
something yeah so there it is the pardon
process if if I may yeah of course the
pardon process is supposed to be very
simple and very direct you go to
www.justice.gov
Parton and you fill out apply for
clemency and it's supposed to be that
easy but what they do is they take your
application and they send it to the FBI
to do a background investigation on you
and they want to know are you sorry for
what you did have you said so in public
have you committed another crime are you
an [__] to people you know all kinds
of different things and then they send
that whole package
to your
prosecutors and they say to the
prosecutors uh John here wants a uh
wants a pardon what do you guys think
about that well this is what they think
this is what they think about just about
everybody then they send it to your
sentencing judge and they ask the judge
who's 99% of the time a former
prosecutor and they say um you wanna you
want to give this guy a pardon and the
judge usually says no no pardon for him
and then it goes to the deputy attorney
general the deputy attorney general says
no no pardon for him then it goes to the
uh white house chief of staff and the
white house chief of staff
um makes a recommendation to the
president that is unless you have money
or influence um these these pardons that
Donald Trump has been giving nobody
applied for those pardons he just gave
them you remember this uh this Green
Beret war criminal that was pardoned at
the very very end of Trump's first term
he didn't apply for a
pardon Fox News talked about his case
every single night for a month and a
half and then he got a pardon
um another one was uh this crooked judge
the the kids for cast judge right he
hadn't applied for a pardon and even
even governor of Pennsylvania Josh
Shapiro said whoa wait a minute where'
this pardon come from literally guy who
ruins the lives of children for money a
judge right he literally sold children
into bondage yes so disgusting so if
you've got you know you don't get Aon or
commutation I think is what that he got
right that guy did he get a part
commutation maybe yeah but if you if
you've got money or you have daily
access to to Fox News and you can get in
the president's face every night or you
have you know a very important and very
well-placed friend who can just walk
into the Oval Office and say hey do me a
solid and pardon this guy otherwise you
know your chances are nil and I I point
out in this piece that I wrote that the
number of Pardons that have been given
by the last you know four or five
presidents
are are dwarfed by the number of Pardons
that used to be given I mean even
Richard Nixon pardoned 22% of the people
who applied well now we're down to more
like 2%
2% yeah what happened to
forgiveness you know when I got home
from prison um I went to the courthouse
in um Arlington Virginia to register to
vote and um they said did you get an
approval from the the governor and I
said' oh I didn't realize that I had to
get an approval from the governor they
said only in Virginia and Florida you
have to get the approval of the governor
I'm like okay so I go on go on to the
governor's website it was uh Terry
mcalli at the time and I I said you know
I'm a convicted felon I I was convicted
of violating the intelligence identities
protection act of
1981 and I I would like the right to
vote I paid my debt to society right
like two weeks later my doorbell rings
at 7 o'clock in the morning and it's a
courier and he's got this big envelope
like this big but it's like a hard stiff
cardboard envelope and I pull it out and
it's this gooral declaration with a big
seal the big gold seal on it and it's
signed by the governor and it's a pardon
it's a gubinatorial pardon it was a
really sweet thing to do I hadn't been
convicted of committing a State Crime
but what it did was it was symbolic and
it allowed me to register to vote that's
nice so I I went to register to vote
again when I got the big certificate and
there's a box have you ever been
convicted of a felony and I said yes
have you been pardoned by the governor
so I checked yes and they said that the
guy who handles your kind of cases and
the woman Winks at me he's on vacation
today and I said oh but today's the last
day to register so that I can vote in
the elction she said don't worry about
it you can vote in the election on the
following Monday this guy from the
courthouse comes to my house and gives
me my voter registration card and he
said we know what you did I wanted to
make this as easy as possible so people
have been awesome it's these presidents
who have been dicks and Mitch McConnell
I'd like to smack in his in his Turtle
face too but that's just me that would
be the final his final moments I think
he's like yeah I think so pretty well
he's pretty well dead as it is because
Mitch McConnell said that if Trump
pardoned and this was the original idea
Trump was going to Pardon Julian Assange
Ed Snowden and me that and and McConnell
didn't know me but he said if Trump uh
pardoned Assange and Snowden that he
couldn't control the Republican caucus
in the Senate and that they would
probably vote to convict him on the
impeachment charges so he dropped our
pardons you know when I was working on
the hill we used to make fun of him
because he lives in this townhouse
that's literally four doors down from
the uh from the heart Senate Office
Building so he lives like literally 150
feet from his office and he used to take
a limo every morning the 150 feet and we
would boo him as he as he drove by like
what a loser well what are your thoughts
on uh Elon Musk and also on USA because
one of the reasons that I I think you're
such a great guest is because you're and
someone to talk to is you don't have
like a particular political formula
right so you're critical of Elon mus
you're also critical of USA tell us
about the connection between USA and the
CIA yeah um you Ted Kennedy once called
usaid the cia's beach head at the uh
State Department